JOSEPH "MIKE" PRINCE

Software Engineer

PERSONAL PROFILE

After spending 10 years as a helicopter mechanic in Special Operations Aviation, I was looking for a career change. A logic and design college course introduced me to the Python language, and after learning the basics, I developed a passion for software development.

CONTACT DETAILS

- Mobile: 931-494-0783
- michaelprince3@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/michaelprince3
- github.com/michaelprince3

PROJECTS

Nutshell Group Project

A JavaScript web application that allows a user to save news, articles, tasks, and events as well as chat with and save friends. Personally responsible for the events section of the site.

Projectile Project Planner

A single page project planning application to save future, active, and completed projects. Built using React with hooks and utilized JSON server for persistent data storage. Styled with MaterialUI and CSS.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Jan 2020 - June 2020

US Army

Various Military Schools 2007-2018

DeVry University Business Management

2016 - 2019

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Software Engineer

Nashville Software School | Jan 2020 - Present

Six-month full-stack web development boot camp with an emphasis on HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python / Django

- Utilized Git/GitHub for version control and issue tracking
- HTML/CSS used to create simple web pages
- JavaScript used to build CRUD functionality in web applications
- Utilized React with hooks for functional component based web design
- Used dbdiagram.io to create entity relationship diagrams
- Utilized JSON to access and manipulate data from external and local APIs
- Utilized Agile SCRUM methodologies for project management
- Participated on development teams during sprints to deliver products on time

Special Operations Aviation

US Army | 2007 - 2018

- Managed 14 employees meeting production requirements in repair and maintenance of aircraft assigned to Special Operations Assault Helicopter Company
- Responsible for the training and certification of 14 employees on regularly updated inspection methods
- Conducted quality control, maintenance, and repair inspections for aircraft systems, resulting in zero incidents over a three-year period
- Managed daily production requirements for a powertrain shop while supervising and mentoring 14 employees
- Received jobs from Production Control Offices and various flight companies for assignment to available personnel
- Completed work orders, authorizations, and job related documentation
- Provided support for US Army programs including Sexual Harassment/Assault Response and Prevention, Equal Opportunity, and Equal Employment Opportunity
- Personally responsible for inspection and repair of \$300 million worth of parent organization's equipment